ARPIT DWIVEDI

Portfolio link: http://arpit-dwivedi.github.io/

+91 9532294061

≥ 8arpitdwivedi798@gmail.com

https://github.com/arpit-dwivedi in www.linkedin.com/in/dwivedi-arpit/

datascienceplus.com/author/arpit-dwivedi/

SUMMARY

Specialist Programmer working on Full Stack development, having experience in developing application on Microsoft technologies. Well acquainted with C# Programming Language, ASP.NET CORE, Angular, microservices, SQL Server, Azure Fundamentals, etc. I am always curious to learn something new.

PERSONAL DETAILS

- DOB 12th January, 1998
- Father's Name- Mr. C.B Dwivedi
- Permanent Address- E-12/1,
 Sarvodaya Nagar, Lko 226016

EDUCATION

- BACHELORS OF TECHNOLOGY (Computer Science Engineering) GLA University, Mathura, U.P. 2016-2020
- SECONDARY SCHOOL
 Rani Laxmi Bai Memorial School,
 Lucknow, U.P. -2015
- HIGH SCHOOL
 Rani Laxmi Bai Memorial School,
 Lucknow ,U.P.-2013

CORE SKILLS

- C#
- Microsoft SQL
- .NET Core Full Stack Web Development.
- Angular
- Microservices
- Typescript
- Azure Fundamentals
- Python
- Machine Learning & Computer Vision

OTHER SKILLS

- Leadership
- Duty Bound
- Ability to Work Under Pressure.
- Writing Skills
- Fast Learner
- · Team Player

EXPERIENCE

• Infosys-

Digital Specialist Engineer
Specialist Programmer

(January 2021 to January 2022) (January 2022 to Present)

- **Key Skills Involved:** C#, SQL Server, ASP.NET Core Web API, Angular 9, microservices, Git, ElasticSearch.
- Currently working for a **Logistics client**.
- Work & Responsibilities
 - Working on analysis, estimates, and low-level designs of requirements based on discussions with clients.
 - Developing APIs, SQL procedures other backendrelated work for the requirement.
 - Working on UI and integration of any new feature.
 - Writing Test Cases and Integration testing for the developed new features.

OTHER RESPONSIBILITIES / TRAININGS

- **DevIncept** Founded an Open-source community, enabling students to learn and collaborate on new tech with help of industry experts.
- **StudentCode_in** Contributed to DiversitAI org, in the open-source contribution program, and worked on image segmentation.
- <u>IOTIOT.in</u> AI Core Tech Skilling Worked on Object Detection, Transfer learning, and hyperparameter tuning of models.

PROJECTS

- **Image segmentation API:** Built a multi-client web application with FastAPI, which takes an image and gives segmentation results in JSON format.
- Object Detection Detect a Specific Object Using both SIFT or ORB.

CERTIFICATIONS & ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- 40k + views on Articles on <u>Datascience+</u> community.
- Paper published in International Journal of Advanced Science and Technology.
- Ranking in top 1% <u>Kaggle Notebook Expert</u>.
- Featured on <u>AI Wall of Fame</u> for being a top performer in IOTIOT.in.
- Participated and successfully completed HacktoberFest 2020, and 2021 Hosted by DigitalOcean.
- Multiple Certifications in Machine Learning/Data Science/Deep Learning by IBM/National Research University Higher School of Economics on Coursera.

EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Successfully organized a 1 month contribution program <u>DCP'21</u>, with 2000+ participants and 50+ Open-Source Projects.
- Have written some technical blogs and Youtube videos to promote free learning.

Date: Signature